

Luke Butcher

Software Engineer Student

CONTACT

lukebutcher.net

luke@lukebutcher.net

0796 527 6449

64 Haslemere Road, Southsea, Portsmouth, PO4 8AZ

REFERENCES

Available upon request



GitHuk



Linked ir

A highly motivated, software engineering student at the University of Portsmouth, This degree combined with 4 years experiance serving in the British Army, Royal Engineers has honed time management, programming and mathematical skills. Seeking a year industrial placement within a leading software company.

Education

University of Portsmouth BSc(Hons) Software Engineering September 2016 - May 2020

First year average: 78% (First class)

Java, Python, SQL, CSS, HTML, time management, team management, communication, working under pressure were some of the skills developed through several projects including writing Java and Python programs to a specification, designing databases, researching computer architecture, designing a computer network as a team for a two floor office and building a website!

Collision simulation, Java

- Working independently from a brief to develop an appropriate solution.
- Breaking the overall goals down into milestones and creating test methods for each.
- Reviewing and refining code at each milestone.
- Advancing knowledge of classes and inheritance as well as documentation.
- Meeting all specifications of the brief and achieving a project grade of 100%

Network Design

- Working from a specification and blue print, as part of a small team of 4.
- Developing a logical design, physical design, cost analysis and simulations.
- •A leading role, organising group deadline, delegating roles and responsibilities.
- Scheduling regular meetings to drive group communication.
- •Identifying when group individual members needed extra guidance or assurance.
- Developing team leading ability.
- Gaining greater understanding of network infrastructure.

Database Development

- Working on a long term project totaling 6 months.
- Developing a full database from a specification.
- Reviewing design as project progresses.
- Creating use cases and entity relationship diagrams.
- Earning 9th place out of 267 students for the unit combined with exam results.

Beal High School September 2003 - July 2009

BTEC level 3 (2009) IT Merit, Distinction
GCSEs (2007) Science AA, Maths B, English CC, History C, PE C,
BTEC level 2 IT pass.

Professional Qualifications October 2011 - July 2015

- •17th Edition Level 3 Award in the Requirements Electrical Installations BS7671:June2008(2011)
- City and Guild NVQ level 3 Certificate in Electrotechnical Technology Installations (Buildings and Structures)
- •Level 2 Contribution to the search and/or disposal function •Over Head Linesman •Combat Engineering Level 1

 Relevant experience

Summer project 2017 June 2017 - September 2017

Developing solutions to the 2016 UK & Ireland Programming Contest in preparation for the 2017 event.

- Evaluate project aims
- •Establish project stages with defined achievable goals for each stage.
- Career history

- Review each stage of the project once completed to look for better/alternative solutions.
- Colaborate via git hub and in person meetings.

BarringtonJames Pharmaceutical Recruitment Consultant (temporary) Januaary 2016 – Febuary 2016

 Problem solving, persuasion and communication were skills developed here for the tasks of having individuals complete the company recruitment form and connecting to the right people for securing positions.

British Army Explosive Ordnance Disposal Team member March 2013 - March 2016

Carried out day to day military activities as well as manning several out of hours duties.

- Working to deadlines for example mitigation and detonation of a 250kg world war two live bombs in central London. Excavation and defusing within 24 hours was essential to allow the public to return to their homes in the surrounding square kilometre.
- Health and safety were key aspects when working as a team of 8 whilst constructing various displays and stands to commemorate 75 years of bomb disposal responsibilities residing with the Army.
- Quickly adapting and integrating into a team is essential within the Army, with tasks lasting from hours to weeks while working under pressure and in discomfort, for example when providing chemical biological radiological and nuclear containment duties throughout the UK on 3hrs standby call out.
- Communication in a formal setting, for example, volunteering as a waiter for a charity boxing and dining night raising over £80,000 for wounded soldiers and their families with all ranks from corporal to major present.
- Presenting and teaching basic military lectures to classes of up to 20 people with practical elements at times.

Military training October 2011 – May 2013

 Became proficient as part of a team and as an individual how to conduct myself within a military environment as well as all the skills required of me in a military career. Including basic training chemical biological nuclear and radiological event containment

Hobbies & Interests

- •I find the potential for AI and machine learning incredibly interesting, following developments via YouTube channel Two Minuet Papers and reading further infomation from their videos with an eye to build my final year project in this field.
- •I am an active member of the University of Portsmouth Softball team currently at the top of division 3 of the solent league promotion to division 2 next season. With training twice a week and games throughout the season this helps to maintain my fitness alongside general cardio workouts. Teamwork and quick judgment are key skills here.
- •I also enjoy debate and learning about more obscure topics and have become the Social Secretary for the University of Portsmouth Spiritual and Pagan society organising some games nights and discussions on various topics from AI ethics to creation myths.